Naziya Tasnim

Halifax, NS B3H 4K5

+1 (902) 402-3062

naziya@cybar.dev

github.com/nazy00

linkedin.com/in/naziya-tasnim

Profile

As a computer science major with a specialization in data analysis and software development, I bring a solid foundation in programming languages such as JavaScript, Python, and C. Throughout my academic career, I have shown an interest in various tech fields, including data analytics, machine learning, and software engineering. My co-op semester experience as a research assistant at Saint Mary's University further fueled my passion for learning and creative problem-solving.

Skills & Interests

Skills: Java, Python, C/C++, Linux, Web Development tools (HTML, CSS, JavaScript and frameworks), ReactJS, Git/Github, R, .NET, Visual Basic, MySQL/noSQL, Unity, C#, Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Powerpoint)

Interests: Full-stack development, Linux, Data Analytics, Game development, Digital Illustration and Design

Work Experience

Saint Mary's University

Halifax, Nova Scotia

Research and Programming Assistant

May 2023 - Sep 2023

- Developed python scripts to mine drug information from pharmaceutical data banks
- Analyzed scraped data using NetworkX to find drug interactions
- Cleaned, managed, and manipulated extensive datasets using Pandas
- Documented peculiarities in collected data and prepared reports on results of the drug interaction analyses to build clear understanding of how data standards vary between sources

Project Experience

Blog Webapp with Custom CMS

Northwood Care, Halifax, Nova Scotia

Full-stack Developer

Jan 2022 - Apr 2022

- Worked with a team of 4 peers for our Mobile App Development course
- Built a 3-page blog website as well as a custom CMS (content management system) admin page
- Created an accessible on-screen keyboard to accommodate the client's typing difficulties caused by Cerebral Palsy
- Implemented the blog as a full-stack web app using Bootstrap, ¡Query, Alpine」S, Node, Express, and MongoDB
- Utilized Agile development process to build the website

K'we - Mi'kmaq Language Learning Game

Eskasoni Immersion School, Eskasoni, Nova Scotia

Game Designer, Developer

Sep 2021 - Jan 2022

- Teamed up with 5 peers as part of our Software Engineering course
- Built a game using RenPy and Unity that children from grades 2 to 5 played at school
- Created assets using Medibang illustration software
- Demonstrated excellent communication skills and ability to work effectively on shared projects with other developers
- Utilized Git to version control the game

Education

Saint Mary's University Halifax, Nova Scotia

Bachelor of Science in Computing Science

Expected Graduation Date: Sep 2024

Major Courses: Software Engineering, Mobile App Development, Systems Security, Computer Prog & Prob Solving (python), Database Systems, Artificial Intelligence